Contact

manaswi.navin@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/navinmanaswi-1a708b8 (LinkedIn) www.navinmanaswi.com (Blog) wwww.datascience2u.com (Personal)

www.youtube.com/watch (Other)

Top Skills

Machine Learning Big Data

Data Mining

Languages

English

Hindi (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Big Data Expert

Core Concepts in Data Analysis

Case Based Intro to Bio Statistics

R Programming

Data Analysis in Genome

Honors-Awards

Authored a book on Higher Science Reviewing a book on Data Mining

Best 3D Modeler and Animator

Authoring a book on Predictive Analytics with R

Top 10 Indian Data Scientist

Publications

with R

Deep Learning with Applications using Pythin

Deep Learning with Applications using Python

Leveraging Machine Learning to save millions

Generative Adversarial Networks with Adversarial Networks

Navin Manaswi

Creating Disruptive Technologies is my passion Bengaluru

Summary

Building an immersive e-shopping experience with latest deep learning, 3D, Augmented & Virtual Reality. Building Retail AR Products

Just launched World's 1st 3D Avatar and Virtual Try-on App.\ WoW Closet

Just Launched World's Store AR App WoW Shopence Just Launching Interior Designing AR App WoW Decor Just Launching Hotel AR

Solved B2B problems in HRTech, Healthcare, Retail and ITSM in SymphonyAl Incubator (www.symphonyai.com) having 1 billion dollar committed fund.

Artificial Intelligence expert who loves to solve problems of Video intelligence, document intelligence, Chatbots and Blockchain.

Google Developers Expert in Machine Learning

Author of the best seller book : Deep Learning with Applications Using Python

Author of a book on GAN (Advanced Deep Learning)

Guest Faculty at IIT Kharagpur for AI courses

Delivered successful Enterprise AI solutions.

Building a new vertical of Al powered hiring

Built AI solutions for giant Retail and ITSM

Executed Deep Learning and Distributed Deep Learning applications in

- 1. Oncology Stage Prediction
- 2. Retail Predictive Analytics and Optimization (using 1.5 Billion transactions)
- 3. Semantic search and ranking using phrase embedding for HR tech

- 4. Telecommunications Analytics (Dynamic Clustering and Classification for automatic ticket generation)
- 5. ITSM chatbot that raises and solves ticket automatically
- 6. Speaker Identification and speech to text and elastic search for video intelligence
- 7. Semantic segmentation to automate the visual search

Recognized as one of top 10 global thought leaders and influencers on Artificial Intelligence

Recognized as one of top 2 global thought leaders and influencers on Augmented & Virtual Reality

Recognized as one of top 10 data scientists of India
Published 4 articles on Data Science in different magazines

Experience

WoWExp Technologies
Founder and CEO
April 2019 - Present (1 year 5 months)
Bangalore

Building Products using Artificial Intelligence and Augmented Reality
Launched World's 1st 3D Avatar and Virtual Try-on App
WoW Avatar App: https://play.google.com/apps/testing/
com.wowexp.wowavatar/join?hl=en-GB
WoW Avatar Lite App: https://play.google.com/apps/testing/
com.wowexp.wowavatarlite

Creating a unique Immersive shopping cum entertainment platform to disrupt retail shopping world by using bleeding edge technologies such as deep learning, 3D, Augmented & Virtual Reality

Built 3D Football Match viewing experience using Al http://infeed.in/first-time-ever-in-india-ai-based-app-launch-wow-avator-future-of-online-shopping-by-ayush-agrawal/

Stealth Mode

Founder of a startup | Al Specialist | Al Evangelist | May 2019 - Present (1 year 4 months)
Solving video intelligence problems

Building an immersive innovative retail product with unique features, perhaps never launched in world

Cracking problems and Building Solution/Product

SymphonyAl

Deep Learning- Senior AI Architect November 2017 - April 2019 (1 year 6 months)

Building a new vertical - Al powered Hiring company from the scratch where I work on NoSQL(document database and graph database), Azure cosmosDB, MongoDB, Data Factory, taxonomy, semantic graph, information extraction tech and deep learning approaches.

Delivered Deep Learning based solutions and products for Healthcare, Retail and ITSM verticals where I used biLSTM, Word Embeddings, Azure and GCP platforms, pySpark, SparkML, SparkSQL, HDInsights, Containers, Dockers and multi-GPU in addition to business knowledge.

Used python and pySpark for all activities

Used Cloud(Azure and GCP) for data storage and data pipeline

Used NoSQL and taxonomy for multiple solutions.

Read and implemented latest deep learning papers for enhancing accuracy.

Reports to Chief Al officer and

Reported to CTO and VP at different point of time

Hired 5+ data scientists and team size went from 4 to 110+ in 1 Year.

First Al professional who is hired in India.

Author http://www.springer.com/in/book/9781484235157

Deep Learning

Authoring a book on Deep Learning

May 2017 - November 2017 (7 months)

Creating a lucid book on Tensorflow and Keras to enable developers and data scientists to develop deep learning applications such as object detector. It will teach basics of Tensorflow and Keras, basics of neural networks including Multi Layer Perceptron, Convolution Neural Networks and Recurrent Neural Networks(and LSTM). Any programmer/developer can use this book to start learning deep learning. Moreover, first chapter focuses on revision of numpy, pandas and scikit-Learn packages that will help you build machine learning models

I am also in process of creating Tensorflow learning sessions on YouTube.

Mantra.ai Chief Data Scientist February 2017 - August 2017 (7 months) Bengaluru Area, India

Co-founder and CXO responsible for delivering AI solutions. Currently developing (human like) chatbots, advanced video intelligence platforms, document intelligence and social media analytics platforms with the help of deep learning algorithms, NLP, Tensorflow, OpenCV, Python and R. Hired and built 14 data science and python developers. I led the big team to develop solutions for multiple clients across verticals.

TECOM Group Dubai Senior Data Scientist August 2016 - January 2017 (6 months) d3-smart city, Dubai Emirate, United Arab Emirates

Data Science Professional working for Smart City-d3, Dubai

CSC UKI Senior Data Scientist June 2015 - August 2016 (1 year 3 months)

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Built automated ticket generation system for a Telecom company using dynamic clustering and real time classification

Built vendor taxonomy classification

Built dashboards using Tableau and data science solutions for managed services

Reported to VP, Strategy and Advisory and worked closely with CEO and sales team

General Mills
Data Scientist
November 2014 - June 2015 (8 months)
Mumbai Area, India

Demand Forecasting, KPIs interdependency, wastage minimization perishable items, shelf management

Ayata

Data Scientist- Machine learning and Statistical August 2014 - October 2014 (3 months)

Kolkata

By using different machine learning and data mining techniques and statistical tools like SPSS, SAS, Statistica and Scripting languages like R, Weka, Python, I do fraud detection, prediction modeling, forecasting and prescriptive analysis.

SPP Lab, IISER Kolkata

Senior Research Fellow(Bio statistician)

May 2014 - August 2014 (4 months)

- 1. Data Mining specially classification, clustering, associations, regression, anomaly detection
- 2. Statistical and Data analysis of expression levels in various transcriptomes
- 3. Creating a pipeline to identify microRNA
- 4. Database management of genomics
- 5. Next Generation Sequencing (Working on Small RNA identification and its target prediction)
- 6. Understanding the different kind of wet lab methods

Freelancing

Bioinformatics Analyst

June 2013 - April 2014 (11 months)

As an expert in R, Perl, BigData and Bioinformatics sequencing tools, I have done some works and projects in bioinformatics and bio statistics. I used various data mining techniques in many projects

Praxis Interactive Technologies

Consultant

December 2010 - May 2013 (2 years 6 months)

As an expert in Statistics, I have guided the team and reviewed the content at all levels. I thoroughly enjoyed my knowledge of descriptive and inferential statistics as well as a good level of applied mathematics.

Transmarket Group

Trading Analyst

June 2008 - March 2009 (10 months)

Did an interesting analysis through computational finance and Did trading Eurodollar derivatives in Chicago Mercantile Exchange.

Advait

Life Skills Trainer cum Public Speaker December 2005 - February 2008 (2 years 3 months)

Did impart training to final year engineering students and management students in the area of Quant skills, basics of analytic and soft skills. Did Public speaking on various occasions in colleges on various topics related to Quant/ Soft skills.

Education

Indian Institute of Technology, Kanpur 5 year Integrated Master(Dual Degee) · (1999 - 2004)

Indian Institute of Management, Ahmedabad Advanced Data Analysis, Business Analytics and Intelligence · (2015 - 2015)